

### PROFILE

Trained in the field of language sciences, my research on non-verbal communication is now extended to the artistic activity that I have developed as a self-taught but with great intensity for twenty years. I came to sculpture to explore hybridization, the putting into perspective of materials, universes, images, languages.

### CONTACT ME



+336 98 61 20 14



emmanuellebaudin7 @gmail.com



25 grande-rue F-39140 Relans

# EMMANUELLE BAUDIN (EBCY)

Artist-author. Semiotician, Educational designer



### EDUCATION

Ph-D in Linguistics, Semiotics and Didactics, University of Franche-Comté, 1998.



### LANGUAGE

Native French. Advanced spanish and english.



### HARD SKILLS

Teacher

Researcher

Educational designer Artistic shaping of objects, emotions, concepts and ideas



### SOFT SKILLS

Organization, Autonomy, Rigour, Adaptability, Open-minded, Creativity, Strength of proposition



### **EXPERIENCES**

## 1993-2011: Courses, Workshops, practical training, seminars, conferences, events.

In French Foreign Language and on specific objectives; Remediation in French; Communication and Language Sciences; History, art history and Initial and continuing training for teachers and trainers; Training of trainers.

### Places, publics and specialities:

- UNIVERSITY OF MAINE: coordination and supervision of training for Chinese students in visual arts Wishing to pursue studies at a French institution, 2009-2011;
- CYPRUS UNIVERSITY: Cypriot students in French studies, 2006-2007;
- CENTRE DE LINGUISTIQUE APPLIQUEE: public of various nationalities, students in French as a foreign language or in initial and continuing teacher training and trainers, Besançon, 1992-2005;
- INTERNATIONAL FRENCH STUDY CENTER of Lyon: public of various nationalities, students in French as a foreign language, 1997-1998;
- UNIVERSITE LUMIERE LYON 2: French students, initial and continuing teacher training, 1997-1998;
- UNIVERSITY JOSZEF ATTILA of Szeged (Hungary): Hungarian students in French studies.
- 1993-1994;
- LYCEE MAESTRO HAEDO DE ZAMORA (Spain): secondary school students Spanish learning French as a foreign language, 1989-1990;
- FRENCH SCHOOL OF ACCRA (Ghana), remediation mission With non-students Francophones attending primary school in French, 2000-2001.

### SINCE 2013: Professional proctice of visual arts, Artistic and cultural mediation

- · Centre Eden, Museum of Natural History, Cuisery (71), 2023-2024;
- Pasteur and science, AAA Association Jura (39), 2022-2023;
- The grocery store of the 7th continent, WWF association for Natural brut & Parking day, in

The Year of Biodiversity, Public Forum, Paris, 2011.

- Discovery of the richness of communication and language, Artothem association (70) / Science Pavilion of Montbéliard (25), 2009;
- Serious and playful linguistic journey through artistic and cultural events, Centre de Linguistique Appliquée, Besançon (25), 1998-2005;
- Tactile encounters with works of art for children with disabilities visual, CREESDEV - Regional Centre for Special Education and Training, Besançon (25), 2005;
- Remediation, animation and school support for children of the French School of Accra (Ghana), 1999-2001.
- Academic research projects on the use of art in learning languages,
   Centre de Linguistique Appliquée, Besançon (25), 1998 -005.

#### Literary texts:

 "La Girafe qui s'était rhumée dans les nuages", first part of a tale published in "Les gardeurs de rêves" [Printed text]: 14th People of the World Writing competition at Épingle à nourrice éditions, DL 2022.
 The rights belong to the author.



### Personal exhibitions:

- · Doctor Noé & Mister Darwin, Cultural center of Château-Chalon (39), juin 2022
- · 2023 Gallery, Lons-le-Saunier (39), juin 2021 et mai 2019
- · Rurality, Hyacinthe Friant High-school mai 2012
- · ArtPol Association, Poligny (39), mai 2013
- · Aquarium, Shoe museum, St-André de la Marche (49), mars-avril 2007
- · Les Pieds dans le plat, Geste Gallery, Besançon (25), septembre 2004.

### Collective exhibitions:

· Baron Martin Museum of Gray (70), december 2023 to february 2024 Teepee Gallery, Salviac (46), summer 2023
 "Fleurmidable", Vill'art, Pesmes (70), summer 2023 · Centre Eden Natural history Museum, Cuisery (71), summer 2023 · "Pasteur and the science", aaa association, Dole (39), Lons-le-Saunier (39) and Lahr in Germany (september 2022 to march 2023) • Open workshops in Jura, and association (october 2020, september 2021 and january 2022) • International Symposium in Baalbeck (Lebanon), september 2018 "L'art se dévoile", Installation of landscape sculptures, Château-Chalon (39), Museum of Urban Arts and Street Art (MAUSA), Toulouse-lesummer 2018 Château (39), summer 2017 "Monsters and Wonders", le Château d'Autrey (70), summer 2017 • "Rendez-vous aux jardins", Installation of landscape sculptures, Lons-le-Saunier City hall (39), june 2017 • 36th salon d'art Seloncourt art fair (25), november 2016 · "Walk along the water", Installation of landscape sculpture, Lux (21), summer 2016. International Symposisum of sculpture, Forges de Fraisans (39), may 2016 • Installation of landscape sculpture, Evolution/ Révolution exhibition, Le Château d'Autrey (70), summer 2016 Installation of landscape sculpture, Seleger Moor floral park (Switzerland), spring 2015 • "Game", Baron Martin Museum of Gray (70), november 2014 to january 2015 • Sculpture International Symposium, Tunisian Association for Environmental Art, Tunis, april 2014 • "Horse", Artothem association, Autrey-les-Gray (70), summer 2013 · "Shores of the 7th continent", Artistic journey in the city, ArtPol association, Dole (39), summer "The 7th continent", Heritage Days, priory of Ruffey sur Seille (39), sept. 2012 • "The 7th continent grocerie store", installation in partnership with the WWF for the biodiversity year, Paris (75), september 2010 Gallery, Hout Bay (Afrique du sud), 2009-2010 • "The 7th continent bar", for Les machines à communiquer, Artothem and the Science of Education Pavilion of Montbéliard, Autrey-les-Gray (70), may to august 2009 • Gallery K, Nicosie (Chypre), 2007 and 2008 • Le Débarcadère gallery, Besançon (25), november 2006, · Festival Entrelacs, Staffelfelden (68), octobre 2006 · Elvina Gallery, Vence (06), summer 2006 • The second look, bicentenary of the death of Claude-Nicolas Ledoux: photos taken in collaboration with Philippe B. Tristan, Doubs (25), fall 2006 • Art'Pol association, hall of the municipality, Salinsles-Bains (39), june 2006 • Elan d'art, édition IV, Corum de Montpellier (34), may 2006 • "Fantastique", Artothem, Autrey-les-Gray (70), sept./ oct. 2004 Galerie K, Besançon (25), 2002
 Sept et demi, Galerie éphémère Le Paris, · "Five", L'Espace d'un soir Gallery, Accra, Ghana, Besançon (25), may 2002 mai 2001 · Adjiringanor, L'Espace d'un soir Gallery, Accra, Ghana, décembre 2000 Ghanamorphose, Alliance Française, Accra, Ghana, mai 2000.

### Vidéos:

https://youtu.be/Z\_103N\_5YPY https://youtu.be/9DqqSuCW3yY